export const SOCIALSTUDIESA2017 = [

{
id: "question1",
question: "1. The whole being of an individual which makes him or her unique is referred to as the",
A: "Character",
B: "confidence",
C: "ego",
D: "personality",
answer: "D. personality",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question: "2. Which of the following factors is the most effective way of helping the individual to develop his or her capabilities?",
A: "Education and training",
B: "Financial assistance",
C: "guidance and counselling",
D: "Personal foresight",
answer: "A. Education and training",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question: "3. The most useful aspect of Maslow’s Theory of Needs for an individual worker in Ghana is",
A: "esteem needs",
B: "security needs",
C: "self-actualization",
D: "social needs",
answer: "B. security needs",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question: "4. An identifiable social characteristic of the adolescent is the",
A: "ability to think about the future",
B: "concern for physical changes in the body",
C: "desire to be self-independent",
D: "desire to gain popularity among members",
answer: "D. desire to gain popularity among members",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question: "5. Responsible adolescent social behavior can best be encouraged through",
A: "good preparation for life",
B: "good preparation for marriage",
C: "knowledge of reproductive system",
D: "knowledge of risks of premarital sex",
answer: "A. good preparation for life",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question: "6. One activity that must be encouraged in modern Ghana because it complements the work of the police is",
A: "communal labour",
B: "funeral rites",
C: "neighbourhood watch",
D: "puberty rites",
answer: "C. neighbourhood watch",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question: "7. The National Flag is important because it",
A: "demonstrates the culture of the country",
B: "depicts the authority of the land",
C: "fosters unity among the people",
D: "shows our colonial past",
answer: "C. fosters unity among the people",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question: "8. The call for the abolishing of widowhood rites and the trokosi system is mainly because",
A: "the United Nations say go",
B: "they are practiced in the rural areas",
C: "they are old fashioned",
D: "they violate human rights",
answer: "D. they violate human rights",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question: "9. The main purpose of marriage in the Ghanaian society is to",
A: "create avenue for legitimate child bearing",
B: "give adult status and sense of importance to people",
C: "provide opportunity for the woman’s to collect bride wealth",
D: "Provide opportunity to engage in economic activities",
answer: "A. create avenue for legitimate child bearing",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question: "10. One consequence of breakdown of marriage in the Ghanaian society is",
A: "brain drains",
B: "child delinquency",
C: "excessive quest for wealth",
D: "high infant mortality",
answer: "B. child delinquency",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question: "11. One major characteristic of matrilocal marriage is that the",
A: "couple moves to live in a resident provided by the man",
B: "couple moves to live in a resident provided by the woman",
C: "man moves to live in the woman’s family house",
D: "woman moves to live in the man’s family house",
answer: "C. man moves to live in the woman's family house",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question: "12. The first step in the process of contracting customary marriage in Ghana is",
A: "knocking",
B: "payment of bride wealth",
C: "period of courtship",
D: "seeking consent of people",
answer: "A. knocking",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question: "13. A group of people who are related by blood, marriage or adoption is known as",
A: "A clan",
B: "a family",
C: "a lineage",
D: "an ethnic group",
answer: "B. a family",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question: "14. Which of the following options relate to the Intestate Succession Law (PNDC Law 111) in Ghana?",
A: "Chieftaincy",
B: "Employment",
C: "Inheritance",
D: "Marriage",
answer: "C. Inheritance",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question: "15. Ideally, genuine love and affection for the child best come from",
A: "Aunts",
B: "friends",
C: "parents",
D: "teachers",
answer: "C. parents",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question: "16. One way of improving the moral standard of the youth is by",
A: "encouraging peer influence",
B: "guidance and counselling",
C: "promoting access to night clubs",
D: "promoting free social media",
answer: "B. guidance and counselling",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question: "17. Religious organizations are agencies of socialization because they help their followers to",
A: "discover hidden truths",
B: "gain eternal life",
C: "live virtuous life",
D: "search for the creator",
answer: "C. live virtuous life",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question: "18. The family is failing in the socialization process because of",
A: "inadequate infrastructure",
B: "impartation of cultural values",
C: "influence of foreign culture",
D: "the provision of character training",
answer: "C. influence of foreign culture",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question: "19. Which of these factors does not compromise the quality of the environment?",
A: "Afforestation",
B: "Construction",
C: "Deforestation",
D: "Urbanization",
answer: "A. Afforestation",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question: "20. Which of the following measures would you primarily recommend for the protection of the physical environment?",
A: "Application of research findings",
B: "Ensuring environmental education",
C: "Ensuring environmental conservation",
D: "Promulgation of environmental laws",
answer: "B. Ensuring environmental education",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question: "21. Education is more useful when the individual is able to acquire knowledge and",
A: "abundant wealth",
B: "a university degree",
C: "professional skills",
D: "social prestige",
answer: "C. professional skills",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question: "22. A country is said to be self-reliant when she",
A: "controls her co-operation with other nations",
B: "controls the world’s major financial institutions",
C: "relies mainly on foreign capital for development",
D: "relies on her own resources and efforts for development",
answer: "D. relies on her own resources and efforts for development",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question: "23. The challenges of political independence in Ghana can best be met through",
A: "cultural heritage",
B: "electing experienced leaders",
C: "formulating policies",
D: "positive attitude to work",
answer: "D. positive attitude to work",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question24",
question: "24. Which of the following factors is not a cause of conflict in Ghana?",
A: "Chieftaincy disputes",
B: "Ethnicity",
C: "Incorruptibility",
D: "partisan politics",
answer: "C. Incorruptibility",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question: "25. The process by which a neutral party is involved in the resolution of conflict between two feuding groups is referred to as",
A: "Consensus building",
B: "mediation",
C: "negotiation",
D: "power sharing",
answer: "B. mediation",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question: "26. Which of the following options is an important quality of a good leader?",
A: "Absolutism",
B: "Foresight",
C: "Potentiality",
D: "Rigidity",
answer: "B. Foresight",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question: "27. Constitutional rule is an important element in nation building because it promotes",
A: "Community development",
B: "Good governance",
C: "Self-appraisal",
D: "self-reliance",
answer: "B. good governance",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question: "28. In a democratic state, the people express their varied vies mainly through",
A: "A free press",
B: "parliament",
C: "public debate",
D: "petition",
answer: "B. parliament",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question: "29. An independent body that safeguards the constitution of Ghana is the",
A: "executive",
B: "judiciary",
C: "legislature",
D: "police",
answer: "B. judiciary",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question: "30. Enjoyment of fundamental human rights of the citizen goes with",
A: "obligation",
B: "probity",
C: "transparency",
D: "reward",
answer: "A. obligation",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question: "31. The main function of commercial banks in Ghana is to",
A: "accept deposits from customers",
B: "control foreign exchange transactions",
C: "control the supply of money in the country",
D: "issue new currencies into the system",
answer: "A. accept deposits from customers",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question: "32. One benefit of science and technology to society is",
A: "Ensuring effective prioritization of projects",
B: "Production of drugs with the correct concentration",
C: "traditional timing of the seasons",
D: "the use of charcoal to reduce salt content in soup",
answer: "B. Production of drugs with the correct concentration",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question: "33. The relationship Ghana has with the Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS) is",
A: "bilateral",
B: "cultural",
C: "multilateral",
D: "political",
answer: "C. multilateral",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question: "34. The critical need for the contribution of the youth to national development means, the youth should",
A: "be given enough money to start business",
B: "be given leadership positions at work places",
C: "enjoy unrestricted freedom in the community",
D: "receive the necessary education and guidance",
answer: "D. receive the necessary education and guidance",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question: "35. The following statements are objectives of the New Partnership for Africa’s Development (NEPAD) except",
A: "eradicating poverty from the continent",
B: "holistic approach to Africa’s development",
C: "regional economic integration",
D: "seeking reparation from colonial masters",
answer: "D. seeking reparation from colonial masters",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question: "36. Which of the following co-operations enjoins countries to send troops to restore peace in another country?",
A: "Economic co-operation",
B: "Political co-operation",
C: "Technical co-operation",
D: "Security co-operation",
answer: "D. Security co-operation",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question: "37. Basically, Ghana’s abundant resources can be effectively utilized through",
A: "acquiring sophisticated equipment",
B: "attracting foreign support",
C: "seeking foreign financial support",
D: "training of highly skilled personnel",
answer: "D. training of highly skilled personnel",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question: "38. The first thing to consider when planning a community project is",
A: "government support",
B: "identification of needs",
C: "source of funding",
D: "the people’s commitment",
answer: "B. identification of needs",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question: "39. An attribute which is not a necessity for an individual to contribute to community development is",
A: "Initiative",
B: "selflessness",
C: "vision",
D: "wealth",
answer: "D. wealth",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question: "40. To overcome the high cost of living in Ghana",
A: "interest on loans from banks must be increased",
B: "production of goods and services must be increased",
C: "the population growth rate must remain at 3%",
D: "inflation rate must be allowed to rise",
answer: "B. production of goods and services must be increased",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question: "41. A project that is made to function continuously over long period of time can be described as",
A: "dependable",
B: "profitable",
C: "sustainable",
D: "valuable",
answer: "C. sustainable",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question42",
question: "42. When taking a loan from the bank, the borrower must first consider",
A: "his or her anticipated income",
B: "the budget for the nuclear family",
C: "the rate of inflation in the country",
D: "the interest rate and terms of payment",
answer: "D. the interest rate and terms of payment",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question43",
question: "43. Many business enterprise incur unmanageable debts because they",
A: "collect loans from the banks",
B: "do not plan their income and expenditure well",
C: "live or set up businesses in urban centres",
D: "work with people outside family circles",
answer: "B. do not plan their income and expenditure well",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question: "44. Which of the following measures cannot be effectively used in breaking the vicious cycle of population growth in Ghana?",
A: "Family planning programmes",
B: "Intensive public education",
C: "The use of contraceptives",
D: "Total ban on immigration",
answer: "D. Total ban on immigration",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question45",
question: "45. Overpopulation can be explained as a situation where the population of a country",
A: "grows at the rate of 3%",
B: "has high morbidity rate",
C: "is less than the available resources",
D: "is more than available resources",
answer: "D. is more than available resources",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question46",
question: "46. One major effect of rural-urban migration on rural communities in Ghana is",
A: "Collapse of rural industries",
B: "Improvement in standard of living",
C: "rapid growth of rural population",
D: "rejuvenation of rural industries",
answer: "A. Collapse of rural industries",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question: "47. The major reason for low productivity in the public sector is",
A: "bureaucracy",
B: "lack of skilled personnel",
C: "negative work attitude",
D: "nepotism",
answer: "C. negative work attitude",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question: "48. A successful business is guided by the principle of",
A: "bureaucracy",
B: "duty consciousness",
C: "democracy",
D: "work ethics",
answer: "D. work ethics",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question49",
question: "49. Which of the following options is not an important means by which the private entrepreneur can sustain his or her business?",
A: "Applying higher skills and technology",
B: "Having a huge amount of capital",
C: "Maintaining high quality products",
D: "Separating personal and business accounts",
answer: "B. Having a huge amount of capital",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question: "50. A quality of an entrepreneur is",
A: "Decision making",
B: "innovativeness",
C: "risk bearing",
D: "supervision",
answer: "B. innovativeness",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]